[ethereal music]
1337.
The world belongs to Men.
But the world remembers an older age.
And so do the Elves.
An odd woman arrives at your court…
Fund her expedition.
Unearth the tomb of the Last Elf Emperor.
Touch the amulet.
Become Elves.
Every ruler. Every courtier. Every pop.
The Red Witches speak of
a gateway between worlds.
Restore the Grand Portal.
Build a network of gateways
across the world.
And march your armies…
…anywhere.
Rediscover the lost Elven arts.
Recruit unique elven regiments and levies.
And field the Magi, a brand new unit type.
Ascend through nine tiers of Elvenkind.
From mortal…
…to Elven Demi-God.
Rule beside the immortal Calaquendi.
Master your elven government
with 18 new government reforms
and estate privileges to wield.
Receive the blessings
of the Divine Spark.
Collect all five blessings
Some with... interesting effects.
Breed genetic traits through marriage
to forge perfect heirs.
More than 35 genetic traits to encounter.
Seek out the powerful bloodlines
of ancient elven houses.
81 elven realms.
15 new advances.
17 new buildings.
4 new trade goods.
18 reforms & privileges.
5 divine blessings.
39 genetic traits.
A portal network spanning continents.
One destiny.
[music fades out]
["I know it's my Destiny"]
[Gimli: "Never trust an Elf!"]